TOTSAWIN JANGPRASERT

5-1-1 Shimorenjaku, Mitaka, Tokyo, Japan • (+81)-080-7427-9136 totsawin.jangprasert@gmail.com

SUMMARY

Throughout my career, I have experienced firsthand how technical best practices and good code quality can make products sustainable. I would dedicate team initial effort to layout technical foundation and team norms. Now I am currently leading a FE team to deliver features at amazing speed without scarifying quality and performance.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Frontend Engineer (Team Lead), PayPay

Nov 2022 - Present

Tech stack: Vue.js, Vuex, Pinia, XState, Vitest, TypeScript, Nx

- Lead a team of 5 FE engineers to deliver all committed products while achieving A ratings in all SonarQube metrics
- Improved Core Web Vitals for the landing page, i.e.,
 - reduced FCP by 85% from 1.89s to 0.29s
 - reduced LCP by 77% from 6.48s to 1.47s
 - reduced CLS by 88% from 0.24 to 0.03
- Improved test coverage percentage from 27% to 80% over 50k lines of codes

Lead Developer, ExxonMobil

Sep 2021 - Oct 2022

Tech stack: Angular, HTML, CSS, NGINX, Azure Kubernetes Service (AKS)

- Mentored frontend developers in the organization through coaching, pair programming and code review
- Led frontend discussions both within and cross teams
- Improved software quality by setting up foundation for Angular application e.g. migrated TSLint to ESLint, replaced Karma and Jasmine with Jest and Angular Testing Library, added Mock Service Worker, and set up local quality check workflow e.g. local SonarQube, and pre-push hook
- Conducted sharing sessions to promote technical best practices and encourage adoption in the organization

Senior Frontend Developer, ExxonMobil

Apr 2018 - Aug 2021

Frontend Developer and Application Support Analyst, ExxonMobil

Jul 2012 - Mar 2018

EDUCATION

Master of Science in Computer Science

Sep 2010 - Apr 2012

The University of Manchester

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology

Jun 2005 - Mar 2009

Sirindhorn International Institute of Technology(SIIT), Thammasat University

LANGUAGES

- Thai: Native Proficiency
- English: Full Professional Proficiency